# Sophie Berger

+1 (236) 862-3848 berger.m.sophie@gmail.com

Computer Science student at UBC with Android, iOS, and AR development experience Microsoft Imagine cup Regional Finalist, and Hackathon winner

linkedin.com/in/sophiemb github.com/SophieMBerger sophiemberger.github.io/

"Strength Insight Report" (from Gallup / CliftonStrengths): Achiever, Strategic, Learner, Futuristic, Focus

#### Skills

Proficient: Java (5 yrs), Swift (2 yrs), Firebase, ARKit Familiar: Kotlin, Python, Unity, Tensorflow, HTML, **CSS** 

## **Experience**

Co-owner of "Mindset" startup 10/2019 – Present iOS Front-end developer/co-owner

- Front-end development on dementia screening iOS app using Swift
- Analyzed iOS UI/UX compatibility
- Wrote a tech-specification document for outsourced development

#### Tailored Apps

05/2019 - 07/2019

iOS Software Developer Intern

- Implemented Firebase authentication/Cloud **Functions**
- Added AR and object recognition using ARKit
- Parsed Json from a database for in-app deep links
- <u>Serialized data</u> using the Codable protocol
- Localized UI using a Fastlane Google-Sheet plugin
- Helped the CTO estimate the time effort/pricing of a Machine Learning project

#### **Competitions**

#### Microsoft Imagine Cup

05/2019

Americas regional final (bit.ly/imaginenekotap)

- In top 12 teams out 30,000+ participants in the Americas
- Presented at the Microsoft Build conference
- Same as "nekoTap" project below

#### 1st place at nwHacks with "nekoTap"

01/2019

Western Canada's largest Hackathon (1000+ participants)

(devpost.com/software/nekotap)

• Android app for improved drug adherence using NFC technology to receive tailored drug information

• <u>Designed</u> animations using Lottie library and implemented Android front-end using Java to increase usability/accessibility within the app

#### Education

BSc in Computer Science

09/ 2018 - 12/ 2022

- + Master of Management:
- 09/ 2018 12/ 2023
- Average = 86.2%, Dean's honor list
- Relevant courses: Models of computation, Software construction

#### "Java Foundations Certified Junior Associate"

03/2017

Awarded by Oracle University

• Completion of Java online certification

### Selected projects

#### Soil TopARgraphy

10/2018 - Present

Android & Unity Developer for UBC Launchpad (eml.ubc.ca/projects/soil-topargraphy/)

- Created an AR app using Unity, Kotlin and Java for Dr. Maja Krzic's soil science class at UBC
- Created Android front-end using Kotlin and Java
- Added UI features to custom AR map in Unity
- Offers more engaging education to 250+ students in the above class
- <u>Utilized</u> Google Maps Android SDK for location
- Presented at "Multidisciplinary Undergraduate Research Conference" at UBC

#### Google NIMA in TensorFlow Lite

07/2019

Proof of concept for TailoredApps (bit.ly/TFLiteGoogleNIMA)

- Converted existing "Neural Image Assessment" models to TensorFlow Lite models using Python
- <u>Developed</u> an iOS project to <u>rank images</u> and determine the "best" overall image using Swift

#### Community Involvement

# Microsoft Student Partner (MSP)

09/2019 - Present

Microsoft

Represented Microsoft and educated about technology on social media/my university campus